Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Identified Photographers, circa 1851-1965; Series I; 672
  - Merrill, Elbridge W.
    - Son-i-yat, also known as the Governor John Green Brady totem pole in Sitka National Historical Park, Sitka, Alaska, circa 1901; 16.7 x 11.5 cm on mount 23.1 x 18.0 cm (Box 9)
      This pole and the accompanying four house pillars were a gift of Son-i-yat, Haida chief of Kasaan, to the district of Alaska
  - Montfort, E.
    Photographer and undertaker in Albuquerque, New Mexico
    - View of the Hotel Montezuma (later Phoenix Hotel) in Montezuma, New Mexico, circa 1886-1888; 11.2 x 19.0 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 9)
    - View of the Hotel Montezuma (later Phoenix Hotel) in Montezuma, New Mexico, circa 1886-1888; 11.9 x 19.1 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 9)
  - Moore
    Photographer in Middletown, Connecticut
    - Studio portrait of Rufus Sage (born 1817) of Cromwell, Connecticut, circa 1880; 15.2 x 10.5 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 9)
  - Moore Brothers
    Photography studio in Telluride, Colorado
    - Telluride, Colorado, circa 1895-1900; 15.4 x 20.4 cm on mount 21.9 x 27.1 cm (Box 9)
  - Moore, Elbridge W.
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Reverend Peter John DeSmet (1801-1873), circa 1888; 14.1 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
    - Flooding of the Columbia River at Portland, Oregon, circa 1888; 11.3 x 19.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
    - Men in floodwaters at the railroad depot in Brownsville, Oregon, circa 1888; 11.3 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
  - Moore, George
    - Snoqualmie Falls, Washington, 1870-1897; 19.1 x 11.0 cm on mount 20.4 x 11.0 cm (Box 9)
    - Copy photograph of a drawing of Chief Seattle (1790-1866) made in 1891 by Ray Coombs after a carte-de-visite photograph created by Edward M. Sammis, circa 1891-1897; 13.6 x 9.8 cm on mount 15.8 x 10.0 cm (Box 9)
  - Morledge, Clarence Grant
    Photographer in Chadron, Nebraska
    - Informal portrait of Dakota Indian men, idnetified as Chief Two Strike, also known as Nomkahpa (1832-1923), Chief Crow Dog, and Chief Night Hawk, 1891; 9.9 x 16.4 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.4 cm (Box 9)
      Inscription in the image: "Leaders of the Hostile Indians at Pine Ridge Agcy., S. D., during the late Sioux War"
  - Morris, Ella, and Samuel I. Morris
    Photographers in Santa Cruz, California
    - Bird's-eye view of Santa Cruz, California, 1886-1887; 12.9 x 21.2 cm on mount 17.8 x 25.4 cm (Box 9)
    - General John Charles Frémont (1813-1890), his wife, Jessie Ann Benton Frémont (1824-1902), and their daughter, Elizabeth Benton Frémont (1842-1919) standing by a redwood tree that bears his name, 1888 May 4; 12.9 x 21.3 cm on mount 17.8 x 25.4 cm (Box 9)
  - Morrison, E. G.
    Photographer in Santa Monica, California
    - Arch Rock, Santa Monica, California, circa 1885; 11.2 x 18.6 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 9)
  - Morrison, Robert C.
    Photographer in Miles City, Montana
    - Portrait of a bootblack identified as Lutz with a dog collar around his neck and sleeping among liquor bottles behind the Bullard Saloon at 6th and Main Street in Miles City, Montana, circa 1885; 13.7 x 10 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
  - Morse, George Daniel
    - Studio portrait of a man and woman wearing a bridal veil, 1881-1895; 19.0 x 12.3 cm on mount 21.5 x 13.0 cm (Box 9)
  - Mullen, James
    Photographer in Lexington, Kentucky
    - Studio portrait of General Leslie Combs (1793-1881), 1868 Sep; 9.1 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 9)
  - Music Box
    The Music Box was a burlesque hall in San Francisco, which would later become the Great American Music Hall
    - Promotional halftone photograph portrait of burlesque dancer Sally Rand (1904-1979), circa 1939-1940; 17.7 x 12.8 cm, unmounted (Box 9)
      Formerly owned by Alfred E. Heller. Purchased from the William Reese Co. on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2005.
      Signed on the recto by Rand
  - Neil
    Photographer in Pendleton, Oregon
    - Studio portrait of two Umatilla Indian women, circa 1880-1890; 13.3 x 10.0 cm on mount 15.5 x 11.0 cm (Box 9)
  - Nevins, George O.
    - West view of the Antlers Hotel, Colorado Springs, Colorado, circa 1890; 12.0 x 19.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
    - The Narrows, Williams Canyon, Colorado, circa 1890; 19.2 x 12.0 cm on mount 21.6 x 13.3 cm (Box 9)
  - Notman Photographic Company
    Photography studio in Boston, Massachusetts
    - Studio portrait of Mary C. Burnham, circa 1877-1890; 14.3 x 10.3 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 9)
  - Notman, William, & Son
    Photography studio in Montreal, Quebec; partnership of William Notman (1826-1891) and William McFarlane Notman (1857-1913)
    - Studio portrait of Sitting Bull, 1885; 14.4 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.1 x 10.9 cm (Box 9)
  - Notman, William McFarlene (1857-1913)
    - Lake Louise, Alberta, circa 1889; 18.5 x 23.8 cm, unmounted (Box 9)
  - Nowack, Mark
    - Union Depot, Saint Paul, Minnesota, 1885-1887; 10.5 x 17.0 cm on mount 10.8 x 17.8 cm (Box 9)
  - Nowell, Frank H. (1864-1950)
    Photographer in Nome, Alaksa, and Seattle, Washignton
    - View of Nome, Alaska, circa 1908; 19.8 x 25.2 cm, unmounted (Box 9)
      Image number 6671
      Image likely forms a portion of a panoramic view
  - Ormsby, Elon D.
    Photographer in Oakland, California
    - Studio portrait of Captain D. B. Finch of the Eliza Anderson steamboat, 1878-1888; 20.0 x 21.1 cm on mount 21.6 x 13.3 cm (Box 9)
      Manuscript on verso: "Capt. Finch of the Eliza Anderson, a pioneer transportation man"
  - Pach
    - Old Californians at the Ocean Hotel, Long Branch, New Jersey, 1877 September 9; 19.0 x 23.5 cm on mount 23.6 x 29.2 cm (Box 9)
      Portrait of members of the Associated Pioneers of the Territorial Days of California at their second annual meeting in Long Branch, New Jersey. Includes Image includes Lewis Leland, Joseph C. Lawrence, H. G. Gibson, Francis C. Clark, H. K. Cummings, Demas Strong, Lorin Palmer, Samuel Curtis Upham (1819-1885), O. C. Pratt, John A. Sutter (1803-1880), R. M. Price, and Robert H. McKune (1823-1894)
  - Pacific & Atlantic Photos, Inc.
    Photographic syndicate formed by the New York Daily News and Chicago Tribune
    - African American soldier in the United States Army with a rifle and posed standing next to a barbed wire fence in Arizona at the international border with Mexico, 1927 March 12; 25.2 x 20.3 cm, unmounted (Box 9)
      Typescript indentification affixed to verso of the print.
      Crop marks written in crayon on the recto of the print
  - Park, Seth (born 1818)
    Photographer in Brantford, Ontario
    - Iroquois man with a club and buffalo robe, possibly Shontzenbraw, circa 1860; 9.1 x 6.1 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.2 cm (Box 9)
  - Parker & Hasselman
    Photographer in Los Angeles, California; partnership of Francis Parker and Hasselman
    - Composite photograph of twenty studio portraits by Francis F. Parker that depict "Soloists of the Jubilee", 1878 Jun; 14.7 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 9)
  - Parker & Johnson
    Photographer in Omaha, Nebraska; partnership of Charles Parker and Ira T. Johnson. They purchased the former studio of William Henry Jackson in 1871
    - Studio portrait of three Pawnee Indian men, circa 1872; 5.8 x 9.3 cm on mount 6.2 x10 cm (Box 9)
  - Parker, Francis F.
    Photographer in El Paso, Texas
    - Nuestra Señora de Guadalupe del Paso, Paso del Norte (Ciudad Juárez), Mexico, 1882-1900; 9.2 x 17.1 cm on mount 10.0 x 17.8 cm (Box 9)
    - Paso del Norte (Ciudad Juárez), Mexico, 1882-1900; 9.2 x 17.1 cm on mount 10.0 x 17.8 cm (Box 9)
    - El Paso, Texas, 1882-1900; 9.2 x 17.1 cm on mount 10.0 x 17.8 cm (Box 9)
      Includes "The Pony Saloon"
  - Parker, Joseph C. (born 1834)
    - Interior of a Pueblo Indian church, probably the San Agustín de la Isleta Mission, Isleta, New Mexico, circa 1880-1890; 11.2 x 19.1 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 9)
    - Sweet Water Dam, from the north side, on the Sweet Water River, San Diego, California, circa 1888; 11.2 x 18.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
      Advertisement on verso for "San Diego Curiosity and Shell Store"
    - Sweet Water Dam, from the south side, on the Sweet Water River, San Diego, California, circa 1888; 11.2 x 18.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
    - Copy photograph of a painting of Hotel del Coronado and beach, from the west, Coronado, California, circa 1890; 10.2 x 18.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 9)
  - Parkhurst, T. Harmon (1883-1952)
    Photographer in San Juan Pueblo and Taos Pueblo, New Mexico
    - Pueblo of San Juan, New Mexico, circa 1930-1940; 16.2 x 26.3 cm, unmounted (Box 10)
    - Pueblo of Taos, New Mexico, circa 1930-1940; 16.2 x 26.3 cm, unmounted (Box 10)
  - Partridge
    Photographer in Portland, Oregon; partnership of brothers, Edward J. Partridge (1856-1891) and William H. Partridge (1858-1939)
    - Ellensburg, Washington Territory, 1884-1889; 11.2 x 19.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 10)
    - Group gathered on the deck of a ship with a mountain in the background, Alaska, 1889; 10.0 x 19.0 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 10)
    - Studio portrait of Marcellus Joseph Luark (born 1840), Methodist minister and assessor for Chehalis County, Washington, circa 1888; 9.2 x 5.9 cm on mount 10.4 x 6.2 cm (Box 10)
  - Pautzke, Otto W.
    Photographer in Ellensburg, Washington
    - Northern Pacific Railroad locomotive number 2108 and crew in Ellensburg, Washington, circa 1908; 15.2 x 21.0 cm on mount 19.3 x 27.1 cm (Box 10)
  - Peake, J. J.
    Photographer in Kelso, Washington
    - Flood in Kelso, Washington, circa 1885; 11.8 x 19.3 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 10)
  - Peavey, Louis (1832-1902)
    Photographer in Faribault, Minnesota
    - Studio portrait of Henry Benjamin Whipple (1822-1901) was the first Episcopal bishop of Minnesota., 1874-1888; 14.2 x 9.2 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 10)
      Inscribed and signed on the verso and recto: "Yours Faithfully, H. B. Whipple"
  - Pendley's Photo Service
    Photography studio in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma
    - Group portrait of eighteen African American women, probably members of the Oklahoma Federation of Colored Women and Girls, circa 1966; 20.7 x 25.3 cm, unmounted (Box 10)
      Removed from Oklahoma Federation of Colored Women's Clubs, Fifty-Sixth Annual Session: Oklahoma Federation of Colored Women and Girls (Muskogee, Oklahoma: Oklahoma State Federation of Colored Women, 1966)
      Purchased from Rayman Americana on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2009
    - Group portrait of twenty African American women wearing white dresses, probably members of the Oklahoma Federation of Colored Women and Girls, as well as an African American man, circa 1966; 20.6 x 25.4 cm, unmounted (Box 10)
  - Pennell & Zellner
    Photographer in Junction City, Kansas; partnership of Joseph Judd Pennell and E. D. Zellner
    - Studio portrait of Thomas Toolan, sergeant in the 7th Cavalry Regiment and 1st Cavalry Regiment, circa 1896; 14.1 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 10)
  - Pennington, William M. (1874-1940)
    Photographer in New Mexico
    - Studio portrait in profile of a Navajo Indian man, identified as Strong-man, posed sitting and wearing a blanket and a cloth headband, circa 1904-1932; 25.4 x 20.5 cm, unmounted (Box 10)
  - Perkins, Alfred Judkins (born 1839)
    - Lake Alvord, Golden Gate Park, San Francisco, California, 1880-1883; 11.0 x 18.7 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
    - Geyser Canyon, Geyserville, Sonoma, circa 1890; 10.8 x 18.6 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
  - Perkins, William S.
    Photographer in Colfax, California
    - Train traversing Long Ravine Bridge, Placer County, California, of the Central Pacific Railroad with another train on a Nevada County Narrow Gauge Railroad at the bottom of the ravine, circa 1875-1901; 11.4 x 19.3 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
  - Perry, Herbert A. (born 1870)
    Photographer in Armour, South Dakota
    - Yankton Indian agency, Greenwood, South Dakota, circa 1900; 9.9 x 14.2 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.6 cm (Box 10)
  - Philippi, Rudolph J.
    Photographer in Redlands, California
    - Farm in Redlands, California with mountains in the distance, 1892 Feb 24; 11.7 x 20.8 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
  - Pickel, Ellsworth
    Photographer in Athena, Oregon
    - Studio portrait of Nook-tip-she-ya, also known as Eat No Meat (1846-1914), an Umatilla Indian man, circa 1895; 13.8 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.3 x 10.6 cm (Box 10)
  - Poley, Horace Swartley
    - View west on Pikes Peak Avenue, Colorado Springs, Colorado with a crowd of men in front of the Colorado Springs Mining Stock Exchange and the Antlers Hotel and Pikes Peak are in the background, 1895-1898; 11.1 x 18.5 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.4 cm (Box 10)
    - At the foot of Pike's Peak, Colorado, 1896; 10.9 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 10)
      Covered wagon with Pike's Peak in the distance Advertisement on verso for "W. H. Wyman Curios"
    - Pikes Peak from Briarhurst Manor in Manitou Springs, Colorado, circa 1900-1910; 19.2 x 10.1 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 10)
      Briarhurst Manor was the home of Dr. William Abraham Bell (1841-1921), an English physician known as a photographer of the American West and a founder and developer of several businesses and towns in Colorado
  - Porter, Milton E.
    Photographer in Albuquerque, New Mexico
    - Pueblo Indian dancers in front of a kiva, circa 1908-1909; 6.3 x 10.2 cm, unmounted (Box 10)
      Verso has advertisement for photographs and photographic supplies
  - Post, Albert B.
    Photographer in Ottumwa, Iowa
    - Studio portrait of a man posed standing with a repeating rifle, circa 1880; 14.3 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 10)
  - Potter, George W. (born 1858)
    - Studio portraits of two women, members of the Salvation Army, holding a banjo and guitar, circa 1900; 2 photographic prints, 13.8 x 9.9 cm on mounts 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 10)
    - Studio portrait of an African American man posed standing and wearing a badge that designates him as a member of the Salvation Army, circa 1900; 13.9 x 10 cm on mount 16.9 x 11.2 cm (Box 10)
  - Prettyman, William S.
    Photographer in Arkansas City, Kansas
    - Portrait of six Osage Indians, circa 1890; 9.8 x 14.0 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 10)
    - Chief Pa-Ship-Pa-Ho, Sac and Fox Indian and council, circa 1890; 9.8 x 14.0 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.6 cm (Box 10)
    - Chief Pa-Ship-Pa-Ho, Sac and Fox Indian, circa 1890; 14.1 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 10)
  - Ragsdale, McArthur Cullen, 1849-1944.
    Photographer in Fort Concho, Texas
    - African American soldiers and hay wagon, Fort Concho, Texas, circa 1875-1880; 5.8 x 9.1 cm on mount 6.3 x 10.5 cm (Box 10)
  - Randall, James J.
    Photographer in Detroit, Michigan
    - Copy photograph of studio portrait, probably an ambrotype, of Henry A. Morrow (1829-1891), Colonel of the 24th Regiment Michigan Volunteers during the American Civil War, circa 1860-1870; 9.7 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.2 cm (Box 10)
      Misidentified as "Colonel Morrill." Advertisement on verso for "Randall's Circassian Cream Wash"
  - Readman, J. B.
    - All Saints Episcopal Church and an adjacent residence, Riverside, California, before 1893 Dec; 11.8 x 19.9 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
    - Residence of O. S. Johnson, Riverside, California, circa 1885-1895; 11.5 x 19.7 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
    - American Indian village, Riverside, California, circa 1885-1895; 11.8 x 19.5 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
      Four Indians in front of a wooden hut. Manuscript inscription on verso states the elderly man in the image is 100 years old
    - Residence of O. T. Dyer, Riverside, California, circa 1885-1895; 11.8 x 19.6 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.5 cm (Box 10)
  - Reed & McKenney
    Photography studio in Georgetown and Central City, Colorado, operated by William H. Reed and Albert H. McKenney
    - View of Central City, Colorado, circa 1873; 14.7 x 19.5 cm on mount 20.4 x 25.3 cm (Box 10)
  - Reese, Martin A.
    Photographer in Santa Cruz, California
    - General John Charles Frémont (1813-1890) standing by a redwood tree that bears his name, 1888 May 4; 12.9 x 21.0 cm on mount 17.8 x 25.3 cm (Box 10)
      Letterpress caption on verso details Santa Cruz attractions
  - Rhine, Gustave C.
    Photographer in Fort Worth, Texas
    - Texas Spring Palace, Fort Worth, Texas, 1889; 10.5 x 14.8 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 10)
  - Rice, A. I. and Moses P. Rice (born 1839)
    Brothers and photographers in Washington, District of Columbia
    - Studio portrait of Elias Cornelius Boudinot (1835-1890), 1874-1876; 15.1 x 10.4 cm on mount 16.2 x 10.8 cm (Box 10)
      Boudinot was a delegate to the Arkansas secession convention, a colonel in the Confederate States Army, and a territorial representative in the Confederate Congress
  - Riley, C. A.
    Photographer in Council Bluffs, Iowa
    - Copy photograph of Conestoga wagons on Broadway, Council Bluffs, Iowa, circa 1898; 14.2 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.6 x 11.0 cm (Box 10)
  - Rinehart, Alfred Evans
    Phtoographer in Denver, Colorado
    - Studio portrait of a man posed standing next to a penny-farthing bicycle, also known as a high wheel, high wheeler, and ordinary bicycle, circa 1885; 14.9 x 10.3 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.9 cm (Box 10)
  - Rogers, Adelbert D. (1844-1917)
    Photographer in Olympia, Washington
    - Studio portrait of Francis Henry (1827-1893), circa 1890; 14.4 x 9.6 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 10)
      Francis Henry of Olympia served as a delegate to both Washington state constitutional conventions
  - Rose & Hopkins
    Photographer in Colorado Springs, Colorado; partnership of John K. Rose and Benjamin Sanderson Hopkins
    - The Gateway and Pike's Peak, Colorado, circa 1886-1901; 10.9 x 17.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 10)
      "Antlers Hotel" and "C. Casser, Colorado Springs, Colo." printed on mat board. Probably refers to Constantine Casser
    - Cathedral Spires in the Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1886-1901; 10.8 x 17.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 10)
    - Balanced Rock in the Garden of the Gods, Colorado, circa 1886-1901; 17.7 x 10.9 cm on mount 20.4 x 12.7 cm (Box 10)
    - Prospect Dome, South Cheyenne Canyon, Colorado, circa 1886-1901; 17.8 x 10.9 cm on mount 20.4 x 12.7 cm (Box 10)
  - Rose, Charles E.
    Photographer in Pueblo, Colorado
    - Portrait of an African American girl, woman, and man in the yard of a house, which also includes corn plants, circa 1910-1920; 12.8 x 17.7 cm on mount 20.3 x 25.4 cm (Box 10)
  - Rothrock, George H. (born 1843)
    - Cottonwood, willow, and ocotillo "Tabernacle" of the Presbyterian Church in Phoenix, Arizona, circa 1879; 10.5 x 16.2 cm on mount 10.6 x 16.3 cm (Box 10)
      Verso text describes the context for the structure
  - Rothwell, Isaac N. (born 1851)
    - Mission San José y San Miguel de Aguayo, San Antonio, Texas, circa 1896-1900; 9.8 x 14.0 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.3 cm (Box 10)
  - Rowe, John F. (born 1837)
    Photographer in Portage La Prairie, Manitoba
    - Studio portrait of a boy and infant, circa 1885; 9.0 x 5.0 cm on mount 10.5 x 6.3 cm (Box 10)
  - Rudy & Clinton
    Photographer in Colorado Springs, Colorado; partnership of J. L. Clinton and W. Ira Rudy
    - Colorado Springs, Colorado with Colorado City and Pike's Peak in the distance, circa 1889; 11.4 x 19.1 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.4 cm (Box 10)
      Manuscript on verso describing view as well as a printed advertisement for the Colorado Midland Railway
  - Russell, John, & Sons
    Photographer in Wimbledon, England; partnership of James Russell, Sr. (1809-1899), James Russell, Jr. (born 1835), Josiah Russell (born 1839), Thomas Russell (1841-1903), Hezekiah Russell (born 1844), and John Lemmon Russell (born 1846)
    - Exterior portrait of C. H. Jackson of 1st Volunteer Battalion of the Lincolnshire County Regiment, winner of the Queen's Prize Gold Medal of the National Rifle Association (of the United Kingdom) in 1886, posed sitting and holding a rifle, 23.7 x 16.7 cm on mount 25.3 x 17.4 cm (Box 10)
      Newspaper clipping pasted to lower right corner of print describes Jackson as winner of the "Queen's Prize" at Wimbledon
  - Rutter, Thomas H. (1837-1925)
    - Wharves at Tacoma, Washington Territory, 1888 Aug 3; 11.4 x 19.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 10)
    - Three lumberjacks chopping down tree, Puget Sound, Washington, 1888-1900; 19.8 x 11.5 cm on mount 21.6 x 13.3 cm (Box 10)
    - Six loggers and large felled tree along the Green River & Northern Railroad, near Palmer, Washington, circa 1891; 11.6 x 19.8 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.6 cm (Box 10)
  - Sainsbury & Johnson
    Photographer in Salt Lake City, Utah; partnership of John Hyrum Sainsbury (1853-1907) and Charles Ellis Johnson (1857-1926)
    - Lion and Beehive Houses, Salt Lake City, Utah, residences of Brigham Young, circa 1890; 12.5 x 20.6 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 10)
  - Sarony, Napoleon (1821-1896)
    - Portrait of William Frederick "Buffalo Bill" Cody (1846-1917) mounted on a horse and holding a rifle, 1886; 14.8 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.4 x 10.7 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of William Merritt Chase (1849-1916), circa 1883; 19.0 x 9.5 cm on mount 20.9 x 9.9 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of Henry Villard (1835-1900), circa 1890; 14.2 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.6 cm (Box 11)
  - Saurman, James S.
    Photographer in Saint Joseph, Missouri
    - A group of Indians flanked by cowboys in front of a grandstand and by a sculpture made of corn that depicts a corn with a crown, probably "king corn", 1885-1887; 12.4 x 19.2 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 11)
  - Savage & Ottinger
    Photographer in Salt Lake City, Utah; partnership of George M. Ottinger (born circa 1832), his son, William Ottinger, and Charles Roscoe Savage (1832-1909)
    - Studio portrait of A. L. Bateman, circa 1870; 8.9 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of James Duane Doty (1799-1865), circa 1865; 8.9 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
      Doty was a land speculator and politician who played an important role in the development of Wisconsin and Utah Territory.
    - Studio portrait of Charles Coulson Rich (1809-1883), circa 1870; 9 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
      Rich was an early leader in the Latter Day Saint movement and served as an apostle of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints
    - Studio portrait of J. B. Scott, circa 1870; 8.9 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of Daniel Hammer Wells (1814-1891), circa 1870; 8.9 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 11)
      Wells was an apostle of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints and the third mayor of Salt Lake City, Utah
  - Savage, Charles Roscoe (1832-1909)
    - Devils Gate, Weber County, Utah, circa 1870; 9.9 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.6 x 6.3 cm (Box 11)
    - Witch Rocks, Echo Canyon, Summit County, Utah, circa 1870; 5.7 x 10.0 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.5 cm (Box 11)
    - Residence of Brigham Young from the University, Salt Lake City, Utah, circa 1872; 5.6 x 9.6 cm on mount 6.4 x 10.6 cm (Box 11)
      View of Lion and Beehive houses looking northeasterly from the Council House, which housed the University of Deseret. South Temple Street and the northwest corner of the block bounded by South Temple and Main streets
    - Palisade Canyon and the Humboldt River, Nevada, circa 1875; 5.5 x 8.7 cm on mount 6.2 x 10.0 cm (Box 11)
    - Green River, Utah, circa 1875; 5.8 x 10.4 cm on mount 6.4 x 10.6 cm (Box 11)
    - Studio portrait of a man, circa 1875; 9.5 x 5.6 cm on mount 10.6 x 6.3 cm (Box 11)
    - Snow shed, Donner Lake, from the Summit, Central Pacific Railroad, California, circa 1888; 10.0 x 15.7 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 11)